Stanslaus N Moriasi Colorado Springs, CO 80921 stan.moriasi@gmail.com

EXPERIENCE SUMMARY

Hands-on experience with different AWS services, integration and migration of existing bare metal solutions into virtualized hosting environments using EC2, S3, VPC, ELB, Auto scaling, with CloudWatch metrics integration. Setting up databases in AWS using RDS including MSSQL, MySQL, MongoDB & Dynamo DB storage using S3 bucket and configuring instance backups to S3 bucket.

EDUCATION

BSc Computer Science, Catholic University of East Africa, Nairobi, Kenya – May 2010

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Red Hat 5.x/6.x/7.x, CentOS 5.x/6.x/7.x, Ubuntu

Scripting Languages Shell, Python.

Infrastructure as Code using CloudFormation and

Terraform

Network troubleshooting

Prometheus/Grafana monitoring

DevOps Tools: Ansible, Jenkins

Web/Application Servers WebLogic, Apache Tomcat,

Nginix

Database: Oracle 11g, 12c

Apache Kafka

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Equalum Inc - Remote

DevOps Engineer November 2018 ~ Present

- Participating in system design planning review and implementation to create enterprise solutions built on AWS and other cloud providers.
- Maintaining the user accounts (IAM), RDS, Route 53 services in AWS cloud.
- Launching Amazon EC2 Cloud Instances using Amazon Images (RHEL/Centos) and Configuring launched instances with respect to specific applications.
- Writing and deploying AWS resources using CloudFormation and Terraform templates.
- Created S3 buckets and managed policies and utilized S3 lifecycle rules for storage and backup on AWS.
- Creating Ansible roles and playbooks to configure, deploy to various environments and maintain software components of existing/new infrastructure.
- Generated Python & UNIX scripts for ad hoc tasks.
- Created CloudWatch alerts for instances and using them in Auto scaling launch configurations.

Fairview Health Services (FHS) Minneapolis, MN

Cloud Engineer April 2015 ~ Nov 2018

- Using AWS Console and AWS CLI for deploying and operating AWS services specifically VPC, EC2, S3, EBS, IAM, ELB, Cloud Formation and Cloud Watch.
- Creating Snapshots and Amazon Machine Images (AMI's) of EC2 Instance for snapshots and creating cloned instances.
- AWS Elastic Block Storage (EBS), various volume types and utilization of different types of EBS volumes based on requirement.
- Creating S3 buckets and also managing policies for S3 buckets and Utilized S3 bucket and Glacier for storage and backup on AWS.
- Architecting and configuring secure VPC through private and public networks in AWS.
- Automating deployment of infrastructure using IAC tools such as CloudFormation and Terraform
- Responsible for the development of current state documentation and knowledge base articles; Update documents regularly, and maintain accurate documentation on system performance and operational activities
- Developed Python Scripts to automate log rotation of multiple logs from web servers.

Medtronic Little Canada, MN

Systems Engineer Aug 2013 ~ April 2015

- Helping with installing and configuring Oracle 10g/11g servers and creation of databases in UNIX, Linux and windows environments.
- Experience in installation, administration, patches, upgrades, Configuration, performance tuning and troubleshooting of Red Hat Linux 4.x/5.x/6.x, Microsoft Windows environments.
- Writing shell scripts to automate migrations, database and files backup, monitoring and resolving server related services like Apache and MySQL.
- Monitoring All Ubuntu and Redhat Servers using Nagios tool and solving issues.
- Day to day operational support and maintenance for RedHat 6&7 servers and Ubuntu servers. Installing RedHat enterprise Linux 6&7 using kickstart configuration.
- Installed, configured, tested and maintained operating systems, application software, and system management.
- Managed different Users and Groups and maintained Systems security.
- Configured Terminal servers with TCP/IP address. Configured Thin Client on both UNIX and Windows.
- Worked as a system administrator for the build and deployments process on the enterprise server.
- Worked with third-party vendors for new project executions related to network support installation, Configuration and Administration of Windows Servers 2000/2003, Active Directory, FTP, DNS, DHCP, TFTP, Linux OS under various LAN and WAN environments.
- Performing upgrades and backups of Cisco router configuration files.

References available upon request